<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Things I have done on noahkernis.com</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Things I have done on noahkernis.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>INSULIN_PUMP</title>
      <link>/projects/05_insulin_pump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/05_insulin_pump/</guid>
      <description>TODO: ADD VIDEO
December, 2019. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University.
Silicone, servo motor, Arduino, OLED, ice packs, LED strip, styrofoam.
INSULIN_PUMP is a large insulin pump where insulin is delivered when a person ‘pumps’ the device like water pump.
The person must first calculate how much insulin they need. Then, pump the lever for the desired amount. The number of of pumps is displayed.
Type 1 Diabetes (T1D) requires continuous work to manage the disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIDI_CAN</title>
      <link>/projects/04_midi_can/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/04_midi_can/</guid>
      <description>May, 2020. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University.
Metal can, Arduino, copper, rotary encoder, Node.js, MIDI
Collaboration with Jake Sherwood.
MIDI_CAN is a networked, multi-mode, instrument/MIDI controller. It can be played by itself or collaboratively over the internet.
The device sends MIDI signals to your DAW of choice. A locally hosted Node server also broadcasts and listens for incoming MIDI commands over the internet, via UDP. Network configuration can be done on a website, hosted on the local server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLEAD_FOR_YOUR_PILLS</title>
      <link>/projects/02_plead_for_your_pills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/02_plead_for_your_pills/</guid>
      <description>TODO: ADD VIDEO
February, 2020. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University. Raspberry Pi, Node.js, Snowboy Hotword Detection, Wood Box, LED, Microphone, Pill Box
Collaboration with Benjamin Moll.
PLEAD_FOR_YOUR_PILLS is critical of the American health care system and the power health insurance providers have over people.
With or without health insurance in the United States, people who need medicines or health services have to deal with arbitrary democracy in order to receive care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELATIVE_CLOCK</title>
      <link>/projects/03_relative_clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/03_relative_clock/</guid>
      <description>February, 2020. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University.
Acrylic, Arduino, OLED, push-buttons
RELATIVE_CLOCK is a desk clock meant to be a reminder of someone we care about. The clock displays the current time, but when it is invert, the time changes.
The time is displayed on a small screen. The clock has buttons on the back to set the time. When the clock is is flipped upside-down, the display rotates 180 degrees and shows a different time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SELF_REINFORCEMENT</title>
      <link>/projects/01_self_reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/01_self_reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>December, 2019. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University. Raspberry Pi, BodyPix.js, WebSockets, Node.js, Wood Box, Mono Panel Mount, Mono Patch Cable
SELF_REINFORCEMENT explores the relationship between HUMANS, COMPUTERS, and how they “see” and interact with each other.
The piece allows for a HUMAN to work with a COMPUTER to create a HUMAN-like form using the video feed from multiple cameras observing the gallery crowd. The video feed is processed in real time by the BodyPix Tenserflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELASTIC_HEART</title>
      <link>/projects/00_elastic_heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/00_elastic_heart/</guid>
      <description>December, 2019. Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University.
Silicone, servo motor, Arduino, OLED, ice packs, LED strip, styrofoam.
Collaboration with Pippa Kelmenson.
ELASTIC_HEART looks at the relationship between humans, their organs, and what it means to transplant an organ.
The transplant process requires a donor, a recipient, and a third party to transport the organ. The person transporting the organ gains another organ for the duration of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>